犯罪心理 前情提要
Previously on "criminal minds"...
局婼頨癟睇熅氻p組的能力
The bureau thinks that my ability to lead this team has been compromised.
這週末我就辭去主管職位
I'm resigning as unit chief at the end of the week.
什麼?
What?
我不是要離開隊伍 我只是不再當主管
I'm not leaving the team. I'm just no longer in charge.
你來當主管 我?
You are. Me?
Barnes女士 很遺憾你哥哥被害了
Ms. Barnes,i'm sorry for your brother's death.
我知道這聽起來像客套話 但我真的很抱歉
I know that sounds like something people say, but I truly am sorry.
謝謝你陪我度過這一切
Thank you for helping me through this.
當然
Of course.
我認為你應該和Tamara Barnes斷絕聯繫
I think you need to cut contact with tamara barnes.
Penelope 她失去了哥哥 她只想要答案 我可沒動心
Penelope,she lost her brother. She just wants answers. I'm not involved.
走吧
Let's go.
我們得快點兒 我們已經很快了
We have to hurry. We are.
離門禁只有十分鐘了 我陪你過去
It's 10 minutes before curfew. I'll get you there.
Ben剛剛算啥意思? 只是個輕吻而已
What just happened with ben? It was just a peck.
那是因為你邊上還有人 下次呢
Only because you weren't alone, but next time…
你今晚會給他發短信嗎?
so are you going to text him tonight?
大概吧 應該要發哦
Maybe. Well,you should.
我不知道 我還有作業沒做
I don't know. I have homework to do still.
那又怎樣 我覺得他很可愛
So what? I guess he is pretty cute.
呃 是吧
不!
No!
我不知道 我覺得這算是升職
I don't know,it sounds like a promotion to me.
是啊 這很複雜
Well,yeah,it… it's complicated.
世事皆複雜
What isn't?
嗯 只是這一切發生得太快
Yeah. It's just everything's happened so fast,
我們甚至還沒來得及告訴其他隊員
I mean,we haven't even had a chance to tell the rest of our team yet.
我還是想謝謝你...
You know,i wanted to thank you again for...
能來參加聽證
Coming to the hearing.
我不知道這麼請求你公不公平
I didn't know if it was fair to ask you.
Tamara 我很樂意幫到你
Tamara,i'm glad I could be there for you.
過去幾周我唯一清醒的時刻
I think that the only time that I have felt sane at all in the past few weeks
就是和你交談的時候
is when i've talked to you.
是嗎? 我...
Really? I...
我覺得只有我一直說個不停呀
I feel like I'm the one who's been doing all the talking here.
你幫我找回了工作的感覺
You've helped me reconnect to my job.
事實上 也找回了我自己
To myself,really.
很高興再次見到你
It's good to see you again.
我也是 見到你太好了
It's really nice to see you,too.
我知道你的新工作責任重大
So,listen, I know that your new job is a lot of responsibility
你會 你也應該付出百分百的精力
and you're gonna have to commit a hundred percent, and you should.
但一旦事情步入正軌了 不如我請你喝東西? 這樣公平了吧?
But maybe when things calm down, i'll buy you a drink? Fair?
好 太公平了
Yeah. It's more than fair.
還有 我要給你點東西
Also,i wanted to give you something.
這是William的 我不能拿
It was william's. I can't take this.
我要你收下 拜託 謝謝你陪伴我
I want you to have it. Please. For being there for me.
如果你像我這樣失去了哥哥 有一個像你這樣的人在身邊 會好很多
When you lose a brother the way that I did, it's nice to have someone like you at my side.
有人能給我解釋下為啥Hotch被降職了?
So,did anyone explain why hotch is stepping down?
Morgan今早就告訴了我們結果而已
All morgan said this morning is that it's happening.
一切事務都照常進行
And it's business as usual.
所以我們應該啥也不說就繼續工作?
So we're just supposed to move forward without any discussion?
出了Foyet這事 我想我們得準備好面對一切
After foyet,i think we'd have to be ready for anything.
選好案件了嗎?
Did you pick a case?
我和Jareau探員今早看了所有申請 我決定調查俄克拉荷馬城的案件
Agent jareau and I reviewed the requests this morning, and i've decided on oklahoma city.
為什麼挑這個?
Why this one?
其他的案件 當地警方都多少掌握了證據
Locals have more evidentiary information in other priorities.
這一件 什麼也沒有 他們最需要我們
This one,they have nothing. They need us the most.
很好
Good.
如果您沒有問題了 我想叫隊員們開會
If that's all, i'd like to gather the team.
我去登記 希望隨時向我匯報
I'll be checking in. I expect to be briefed.
好的 長官 如果你想要隱私 可以用我的辦公室
Yes,ma'am. If you need privacy, please use my office.
沒事了 我們談完了
That's ok. We're done here.
等我們回來 我會收拾乾淨 辦公室都歸你了
And when we get back, i'll clear everything out and it'll be all yours.
Hotch 我不要你的辦公室 我同意Hotchner探員的意見
Hotch,i don't want your office. I agree with agent hotchner.
主管需要一個妥當的辦公室
The team leader needs a proper office.
恕我直言 Strauss女士 既然你們兩位都對我接任主管充滿信任
All due respect, ms. Strauss, but both of you have trusted me to step in as acting unit chief.
我請求您尊重我的決定
I'm asking that you respect my decision.
我決定我不需要Hotch的辦公室 那是他的一方天地
I've decided that I don't want hotch's office. That's where he belongs.
如果有需要 我們可以日後再討論此事
If necessary,we can discuss this again at a later date,
但現在 我們真的要開始調查案件了
but right now,we really need to get started on this case.
夥計們 把Rossi叫來
Guys. Grab rossi.
這是Megan Chertow 和她的朋友Bina Sukarto
This is megan chertow and her friend bina sukarto,
都17歲 兩天前的晚上在一車庫被發現 頸動脈被切斷
both 17,found 2 nights ago in a parking garage, carotids severed.
這是John O'heron 61歲
This is john o'heron,61.
四天前在木叢中被發現 頭部被鈍器擊傷而死
He was found dead in a wooded area 4 days ago, blunt force trauma to the head.
行兇方式不同
Different m.O.
被害者背景也完全不同
And completely different victimology.
這些案件是怎麼聯繫起來的? 他們的眼睛都被取走了
How are the cases linked? Their eyes have been removed.
他是個剜眼者 這還有名字?
Oh,he's an enucleator. There's a name for this?
這是一種非常罕見的犯罪行為
It's a rare subset of criminal behavior,
但對於好攻擊的剜眼者 的確有案例研究
but there have been case studies of assaultive enucleators.
他們中的絕大多數都有精神疾病
The overwhelming majority of them suffer from diagnosed mental disorders.
通常是男性 不善社交 殺人都沒有章法又草率
And they're usually males, lack social skills, their kills are disorganized and sloppy.
典型的剜出者挖出眼睛 但一般不會把眼睛帶走
The typical enucleator gouges the eyes out, but he doesn't normally take them with him.
這人帶走了?
This guy did?
我們要搞清楚原因
We need to figure out why.
兩起謀殺間有明顯的轉變
There are noticeable shifts from the first to second murder.
行兇場所從隱蔽之處變成了公共區域
He goes from killing in seclusion to a public place.
被害者也從一個變成了兩個
And he escalated from one victim to 2.
我最擔心的是 兩起案件間隔不到48小時
What concerns me most is there's less than 48 hours between the murders.
所以我選擇了這個案件
That's why I chose this case.
基於我們對剜眼者的瞭解 他們幾乎都會多次重複犯案
And from what we know about enucleators, they're almost always multiple repeat offenders.
正是 也就是說他馬上就會再開殺戒
Exactly. Which means he's going to need to kill again soon.
30分鐘後飛機上見
All right. Let's meet on the plane in 30.
犯罪心理 第五季 第6集 眼殤
Criminal Minds Season05 Episode06 The Eyes Have It
"若是你的右眼叫你跌倒 就剜出來丟掉"
"and if thy right eye offend thee, pluck it out and cast it from thee."
馬太福音 5:29
matthew 5:29.
幾位被害者的眼睛顏色不同
The color of all the victims' eyes are different,
也許這在被害者研究中並不重要了
so that probably doesn't factor in to victimology.
更可能是 他從這些眼堿搢鴗F什麼
It's more likely what he sees in the eyes.
案件研究表明大多數剜眼者都有妄想癥
Case studies show that most enucleators suffer from delusions.
他們聽到聲音 從人們眼堿搢鴘F西
They hear voices and see things in people's eyes.
通常是邪惡的幻覺 他們認為自己的行為是在摧毀惡魔
Usually something evil. They're driven to enucleate to destroy the devil.
這就指向了最近剛從 收容所或精神病院出來的人
It points to someone who may have been institutionalized and recently released.
我叫Garcia去查
I'll have garcia start looking.
好了 告訴我 這些案件有哪些不尋常?
All right,so talk to me. What makes these attacks so different?
第一位被害者頭部遭多重鈍器襲擊 帶了更多個人恩怨
With victim one,there were multiple blunt force strikes to the head… a more personal kill.
他處理了屍體 也許是反偵查手段
And he disposed of the body, maybe as a forensic countermeasure.
第二起謀殺就不那麼個人化了 更投機
The next murders seemed less personal, more opportunistic.
我想我們該查查 為什麼第一個被害者被毆致死
I think we need to look at why the first victim was bludgeoned and dumped.
也許不明嫌犯認識他
Perhaps the unsub knew him.
Prentiss 你去棄屍場地
Prentiss,i want you to go to the disposal site,
查查為什麼他被丟在那兒
see if you can figure out why he was dumped there.
Rossi 我和你去昨晚的罪案現場
Rossi,you and I are gonna go to last night's crime scene.
實際上 兩個女孩的家長說 要和我們的主管談談
Actually,uh, the girls' families asked to speak to our team leader.
好吧
All right.
這樣的話 Rossi 你一個人去現場
Ok,in that case, rossi,you can handle the crime scene solo.
JJ 你跟著我 Hotch Reid 你們去調查John O'heron的生平
Jj,you're with me, and,hotch,reid, I want you to get into john o'heron's life,
看看有什麼能導致私人動機的
see if anything at all points to a personal motive.
俄克拉荷馬城警局 俄克拉荷馬州
我是Phil Brantley 謝謝你們能來
Phil brantley. Appreciate you all coming.
我是Hotchner探員 這是Reid博士 團隊其他成員稍後就到
Agent hotchner. This is dr. Reid. You'll meet the rest of the team later.
這個給你 好
Here's one. Excellent.
這兒是發現第一具屍體的地方 就在城外
Ok,here's where the first body was found, just outside of town.
昨晚的謀殺在這
And last night's murders were here.
差了大概22英里
And that's about 22 miles apart.
這不太正常 什麼?
That's unusual. What?
連環殺手的作案範圍一般更小
Serial killers usually have a smaller kill zone.
這是我們的技術分析員 嘿Garcia 我開了免提
It's our technical analyst. Hey,garcia, you're on speaker phone.
我查了最近出院的精神病人 其中有剜眼
So,i looked up recently released mental health patients who have a history of eye gouging,
或攻擊眼部前科 以及其他 對眼睛和眼窩有"特殊"癖好的
eye assault, and other gross things you can do to eyes and sockets.
那媕Y沒有俄城居民
And there's no bingo for okie city residents.
最近有什麼襲擊眼睛的案子嗎?
Any other recent attacks involving assaults on eyes?
九個月前有一起 但不可能 他還在牢
There's one 9 months ago. He's not your guy 'cause he's in jail.
我們一會再打給你
We'll call you later.
明白 招手招手 再見
104,breaker breaker. Bye.
你覺得他剛從精神病院出來?
You think he's fresh out of an asylum?
或者他剛剛從被禁錮的狀態中獲得自由
Either that or he's been held somewhere and he's now free.
我們見過襲擊眼睛的案件 酒吧鬥毆 家庭暴力啥的
We've seen eye assaults before, you know,bar brawls,rage, domestic abuse cases.
但都沒有像這樣
But nothing like this.
他要這些眼睛到底幹嗎用?
What the hell's he doing with the eyes?
也許當成某種戰利品來收集
He could be collecting them as a trophy of some sort.
它們不可能像戰利品那樣長時間保存
They wouldn't keep long as trophies.
眼睛的80%是玻璃體液 本質上就是水
Eyes are 80% vitreous humor, which is essentially water.
幾個小時後就會變得渾濁乾枯
After a few hours,they begin to get cloudy and wilt.
還有別的理論嗎?
Any other theories?
也曾有這樣的案子 挖出眼球後 精神病人會吃掉它們
There have been cases where after enucleation, mental patients have consumed the eyeballs.
你是認真的嗎?
Are you serious?
謝謝你們能來 應該的
Thank you for coming here. It's no problem.
我們不能離開房子 我們要哀悼三天
We can't leave our house. We have to mourn for 3 days.
佛教儀式? 是的
Buddhist rituals? Yes.
你妹妹昨晚出門時打過電話給你嗎?
Did your sister call you while she was out last night?
沒有 我就知道出事了 她總是在門禁前回家
No. I knew something was wrong. She always comes home by curfew.
你見過這男人嗎?
Does this man look familiar to you?
沒有 為什麼這麼問?
No. Why do you ask?
我們相信你妹妹和他 被同一個兇手殺害
We believe he and your sister were killed by the same person.
這能幫我們排除 被害者之間的聯繫
It helps us to rule out any connection between the victims,
看起來你妹妹被殺是個隨機事件
and it tells us that your sister was most likely attacked at random.
謝謝你 謝謝
Oh,thank you. Thank you.
我要求和你們談話 是因為需要你們幫忙
I asked to speak to you because we need you to do something for us.
沒事 慢慢來
It's ok. Take your time.
祖母說她昨晚看到了Bina的魂
Grandma said she saw bina's ghost last night.
她的眼睛就是兩個大黑洞
Her eyes were just big black holes.
Bina在找她的眼睛
Bina was looking for her eyes.
祖母說Bina被詛咒了
She says bina's cursed.
她無法安息 她永遠要尋找她的眼睛
She can't rest. She's stuck for eternity looking for her eyes.
我們想火葬她
We want to cremate her.
但我們要全部的她
But we need all of her.
你們能找到她的眼睛嗎?
Can you find her eyes for us?
我們會盡力
We will try.
但現實一點說 不一定能找到
But realistically, we may not be able to.
那她會永遠被詛咒
Then she will be cursed forever.
永不得安息
She may never rest in peace.
O'heron的朋友說他有酗酒嗜好
O'heron's friends say he has a history of drunken behavior,
但他們不知道誰跟他有仇
but they don't know anybody with a grudge against him.
他最後出現是在一個酒吧
He was last seen leaving a bar.
當班的酒保說他是平安離開的
Bartender on duty said he left without incident.
之後他去哪了?
Where did he go after that?
我查了John O'heron被拋屍的地點
I checked out the disposal site where john o'heron's body was dumped.
是條荒蕪的農場路
It's a remote farm road.
不明嫌犯不是碰巧這麼幹的 他知道那
The unsub didn't just stumble on it,he knows it.
我們需要一份 在那附近工作或居住的人的名單
We need a list of people who work or live near the area.
我有種不好的預感 為什麼?
I got a bad feeling about this guy. Why is that?
他選了停車場 說明他很有耐心
He chose that parking garage. He was patient.
他躲起來 等待對的時間地點 以及受害人
He hid and waited for the right victims and the right time and place.
然後閃電攻擊他們 這都是計劃好的
He blitzed them. It was all strategic.
這對一個典型的剜眼者來說太有條理了
That sounds way too organized for a typical enucleator.
而且他作案間沒有冷卻期
Add to that his lack of a coolingoff period between kills,
想搶在他之前很難
it's not gonna be easy to get ahead of him.
我剛和法醫通過電話
I just got off the phone with the m.E.
她說有些東西我們得看看
She says there's something we should see.
眼球由六種不同的肌肉 脂肪組織 和視神經牽制於眼窩中
The eyeball is held in the socket by 6 different muscles, fatty tissue, and the optic nerves.
這是John O'heron的眼窩照片
These are pictures of john o'heron's eye sockets.
看到突出的視神經了?
See the optic nerves protruding?
外傷 是被扯掉的 也許是用手
Trauma. They were ripped out. Maybe with fingers.
現在來對比桌上的屍體看看
Now compare this to my body on the table.
內部平滑 沒有瘀傷 沒有外傷跡象
Smooth inside,no bruising, no sign of trauma.
視神經縮回肌肉 並且邊緣很乾淨
Optic nerves retracted into the muscle and they have a clean edge.
這麼說 是仔細切割出來的
So you're saying these were cut out.
用邊緣鋒利的工具
With a sharpedged tool.
他努力不剪到眼窩或者眼瞼
He managed to avoid cutting the sockets or the eyelids.
這是精細活兒
This was precise work.
只有醫生才能幹?
The kind of work only a doctor could do?
我只是說 這兩個女孩 都切除得異常乾淨
All I'm saying is that with both of these girls, it was a clean excision.
所以 他對第一個很粗魯 對其他的卻很精細
Ok,so he was crude with the first victim, surgical with the others.
他為了挖掉眼鏡廢了太大功夫 肯定不會毀掉它們
The amount of effort he's going through to remove the eyes now, he wouldn't destroy them.
他是要保存起來
He's keeping them.
雖然隱蔽 但仍是公共場所
It's secluded,but he chose a public spot again.
他不怕被抓
He's not afraid to get caught.
這和其他犯罪現場很遠 他為什麼來這兒?
This is far from the other crime scenes. What brought him here?
好吧 他這次只殺了一個
Well,he only killed one person this time.
本可以更多
It could have been more.
嘿 我們在附近找到一輛車
Hey,we found a car parked nearby.
從車管部門的照片上確認了她的身份
I.D.'D her from a dmv photo.
Tracy  Copper 32歲 丈夫說她是慢跑愛好者
Tracy copper,32. Husband said she was an avid jogger.
脖子上一處刀傷 眼睛不見了
Single knife wound to the neck, eyes are missing.
跟上次一樣切得很小心
Cut out as carefully as the last ones.
嘿 Garcia 我們有了本地醫生的名單 但需要再做篩選
Hey,garcia. So we have the list of local doctors, but we need to back it up one step.
我該幹嘛呢 我的小美人?
Where shall I splice, my pretties?
把有違法記錄的醫生名單給我 比如醫療事故訴訟
Give me a list of all doctors who've had infractions like malpractice suits.
好了 接下來呢
Got it. Bouncing your way.
縮小到眼科醫生
Narrow it down to eye specialists.
哇哦 還是有很多名字 那我們瞭解多點再打給你
Whoo,that's still a lot of names. We'll chip away when we know more.
嘿 等等 掛電話之前 我的小Morgan干的怎麼樣?
Hey,wait. Before you hang up, how's my morgan doing?
很好 我當然知道我男人好啦
Fine. I know the man is fine.
我是問他當頭兒當得怎麼樣?
How's he holding up as head honcho?
好吧 他有壓力 但他頂得住
Well,he's stressed, but he's on top of it.
說到這個 你倒是可以為他做點什麼
Speaking of which, there is something you could do for him.
說吧
Name it.
他肯定又是躲在樹叢媯扔
He must have hidden in these trees lying in wait again.
所以他是選了地點後隨機選擇受害人
So he picked his location and then waited for a victim of opportunity.
他突襲她 因為缺乏社交技巧 無法吸引別人
He blitzes her because he lacks the social skills to charm.
感覺跟停車場的那一起如出一轍
That feels like the same pattern as the girls in the parking lot.
但停車場很安靜
But he was quiet in the parking lot.
他如果躲在樹叢 有太多干樹枝了
If he hid in these trees, there's too much dry brush.
會很吵 不可能 這樣太草率
He would have made noise. No,it's too sloppy for him.
她是狂熱的慢跑愛好者
She was a serious jogger.
如果她聽到動靜 還是有機會逃脫的
If she'd heard him, she might have been able to outrun him.
除非他用別的辦法驚到她了 夥計們
Unless he surprised her some other way. Guys.
這是什麼? 絆索
What is that? A tripwire.
我們得看看她的腳踝
We need to look at her ankles.
他用絆索把她給絆倒了
He used the tripwire to get her off her feet.
她受到驚嚇 沒時間逃跑
She's stunned and she doesn't have time to run away.
他設了陷阱
He laid a trap for her.
再加上他切她脖子的方式
All this,plus the way he bleeds her at the neck.
這是獵手的行為
It's the behavior of a game hunter.
狩獵是這個城市文化的重要組成部分
Hunting's a big part of this city's culture.
那是獵捕動物 什麼導致他開始獵捕人類了?
Yeah,hunting animals is. What triggered him to start hunting humans?
這傢伙拿走人眼睛 顯然是心緒受到干擾
This guys king yeah,hupeople's eyes,is. So he's definitely disturbed.
我不解的是 這種人通常心慌意亂 行事草率
What bugs me is that people like this usually unravel, get sloppy.
但這傢伙卻越來越好
And this guy's only getting better.
他們回來了
They're back.
Morgan 我一直在這堭給q話 怎麼了?
Morgan,i'm fielding calls left and right here. What's happening?
案子變成全國性新聞了 他們稱他為眼球掠奪者
Case made national news. They're starting to call him the eye snatcher.
好吧 嗯 你去準備個小型記者招待會
All right,um, you're gonna hold a small, controlled press conference.
回答他們問題 但盡量別提那個名字
Answer their questions, but try to squash that name.
我希望人們有所警覺 但不希望大家把他想成一個怪物
I want the people to be aware, but I do not want to make a bogeyman out of this guy.
明白嗎? 好 是的
You understand? Yeah. Yeah.
還有事嗎? 你不接Strauss的電話
Is there something else? You're not answering strauss' calls.
她只是想監視我們 她可以等
She's just trying to keep tabs. She can wait.
Morgan 也許你現在該回下電話
Morgan. Maybe you should take the time to field the call.
Hotch 我們得建立知情者熱線
Hotch,we have to set up a tip line.
我們得重新看下JJ的談話要點 側寫還沒出來
We have to go over jj's talking points. We haven't gotten the profile out yet.
這些都比應付Strauss重要
All of that takes priority over dealing with strauss.
我明白 我們來幫你弄 你去和她談談
I understand all that. Let us help you set up strategy while you talk to her.
進一步行動之前跟你匯合
We'll regroup with you before we proceed.
要應付的已經夠多了 相信我 跟她再杠上沒好處
We have enough battles. Believe me,you don't want to fight her,too.
我們先側寫出來 我就去跟Strauss談
Let me get this profile out, and then i'll go talk to strauss.
他做得很好 是啊
He's doing a good job. He is.
你想過這要怎麼結束嗎?
Have you thought about how this is going to end?
你指什麼?
What do you mean?
Morgan當主管是暫時的
Morgan as our unit chief is a temporary thing.
是
It is.
他是天生的領導 他很擅長
He's a natural leader. He'll excel.
到時候需要他做回組員時 該怎麼辦?
What happens when he's asked to step down?
我們相信 不明疑犯認識第一個受害者 而其他則是隨機選擇
We believe that our unsub may have known his first victim, yet the rest were random.
大部分剜眼者精神失常 攻擊時瘋狂而草率
Most enucleators have a mental disorder and are frenzied and sloppy when they attack.
這個卻很能克制
This one has more control.
我們不用別名稱呼他
We are not calling him by any nickname.
他只是FBI要逮捕的一個兇手
He is simply a murderer that the fbi is trying to apprehend.
他耐心等待著置受害人於死地 知道如何下刀好放血
He lays in wait to kill his victims, knows how to cut them so they bleed out.
說明他也許有狩獵的背景
This indicates he might have a hunting background.
我們提醒市民夜晚高度警惕
We're urging citizens to be hypervigilant at night.
他在城堣ㄕP地區的公開場所殺人
He is killing in different areas of the city in public places.
他作案區域很廣 也許是和他的遷徙習慣有關
His large kill zone could be related to some type of travel pattern in his life,
說明這些小區很舒適
which indicates a comfort with these neighborhoods.
為什麼突然的他開始每天殺人?
Why,all of a sudden, is he killing people every day?
這種加速 也許是由一種自我加壓的時間線造成
The escalation might be caused by a selfimposed time line.
他不得不殺這麼多人 挖走眼睛 來完成一項任務
He has to murder so many people, take this many eyes, to accomplish a task.
所以他瘋了 但他卻有使命?
So he's crazy, but he's got a mission?
可以這麼說
Actually,yes.
他依著自己的幻覺 來進行這場殺戮
He's acting on a delusion that's fueling this murder spree.
比如Herbert Mullin
For example, a man named herbert mullin.
他害怕災難性地震襲擊加州
He had a fear of a catastrophic earthquake hitting california.
他相信通過殺人 並供奉他們的血給大地
Now,he believed that by killing people and offering their blood as a sacrifice to the earth,
就可以阻止地震
he could prevent an earthquake.
他是偏執型精神分裂者 他的幻覺使他殺了13個人
He was a paranoid schizophrenic, and his delusion led him to kill 13 people.
那我們巡街的時候該注意些什麼?
Uh,what should we look for when we're on the streets?
我們確信他是白人男性 27到35歲
We believe he's a white male,27 to 35.
我們確信他開貨車 或是有可卸倉的小型貨車
We believe he is driving a van or a pickup truck with a removable cab.
一些便宜的東西 可以弄得血淋淋又容易洗掉
Something utilitarian that can get bloody and wash out easily.
可能還曾申請狩獵執照
He may also have applied for hunting licenses.
他受過某種醫療外科訓練 但沒能走上職業道路
He has some sort of medical or surgical training but fell short of making a career out of it.
他曾經在過渡療養所 或是治療機構待過
He may have been in a halfway house or have been granted leave from a treatment facility.
也許家人將他接走 現在他回來了
Maybe his family moved him away and now he's back.
如果你知道符合以上描述的人 請撥打我們的熱線
If you know anyone who fits these types of scenarios, please call our tip line.
不明嫌犯在晚上殺人 使用狩獵策略 還十分耐心
Our unsub kills at night, employs hunting tactics, and is patient.
他一直等到能和受害人獨處
He will wait until he can be alone with his victims.
Strauss長官 你終於肯接我電話了?
Chief strauss. You're answering my calls now?
我為早上的事情道歉 但我肯定你能明白我們有多忙
Listen,i apologize for this morning, but I'm sure you can understand how busy we were.
所以今晚是什麼策略?
So what's the strategy tonight?
我和組員會去鎮上 幫助地方警力組織巡邏
I have the team visiting precincts all over town helping locals set up patrol.
媒體提醒居民高度警惕
And media outlets are warning citizens to be hypervigilant.
嫌疑犯呢?
What about suspects?
還沒什麼線索
Nothing viable yet.
也就是說你今晚抓不到他了
So ultimately, you're no closer to catching him tonight.
相信我 我非常明白 講話這會兒他正在尋找獵物呢
Ust me,i well aware that he is probably out there hunting as we speak.
如果明天醒來發現有更多受害人 我負全責
Now,if I wake up in the morning and there are more victims, that is all on me.
我不是在為難你
Look, I'm not criticizing you.
實際上 很多人信任你 想看你成功
In fact,there are a lot of people who have faith in you and want to see you succeed.
你明白嗎? 是的 女士
Do you understand that? Yes,ma'am.
我只是隨便問問 確認下你們的團隊是否仍然完好
I'm just checking in to make sure your team is intact
並且你工作需要的一切都不缺
and that you have everything you need to do your job.
這個小組很可靠 我們會完成任務的
This team is solid, and we will get the job done.
我們明天再聯繫
We'll touch base tomorrow.
我害怕去上班
I'm dreading going to work.
你總是這麼說
You always say that.
嘿 我會開始找份新工作
Hey,i'll start looking for a new job.
明天早上拿份兒報紙 把適合你的圈出來
We'll grab a paper in the morning and start circling whatever looks good to you.
你聽到什麼沒?
Did you hear something?
好奇怪
That's weird.
我看見有人
I see someone.
喂!
Hello!
喂?
Hello?
Wes? 他到底在幹嘛?
Wes? What the hell's he doing?
我好怕
I'm freaking out.
這堥S信號
There's no reception.
快走
Let's go.
不 Sandy 別走這邊
No,sandy. Not that way.
Wes 你看到沒? 安靜 寶貝 他會聽到的
Wes,can you see? Quiet,baby. He can hear us.
他在我們後面 到我前面來
He's behind us. Get in front of me.
我看不見
I can't see anything.
上車去 就在山下
Get to the car. Down the hill.
快快快
Go. Go,go.
快 Sandy 快跑
Go,sandy. Go.
Wes Wes?
Wes. Wes?
Wes
Wes.
不 不要
No,please don't.
還以為我比大家都來得早
thought i'd beat everyone here.
不
No.
你通宵在這?
You here all night?
不能再通宵了啊
You know you can't do that again,right?
Rossi 你走進來的時候 我真以為你要告訴我又有受害者
Rossi, when you walked in here, I really thought you were gonna tell me that there was another victim.
我們一點抓到這傢伙的運氣也沒有
We're having no luck at all trying to find this guy on paper.
所以我們得緩一緩 睡一下 神清氣爽地回來
That's why we step away, get some sleep, come back fresh.
我們在找一個醫生 又是獵人 又有精神疾病
We're looking for a doctor who is also a hunter and a former mental patient
喜歡挖人眼球
who happens to be cutting people's eyes out.
相信側寫 我們抓到他時 會知道側寫都是對的
Trust the profile. When we get him, it'll all make sense.
早上好 不 一點也不好
Good morning. No,it isn't.
不要告訴我
Don't tell me.
一男一女
A male and a female.
他又開始一次殺兩個?
He's back to killing 2?
但這次犯罪現場有些不同
There's something different about this crime scene, though.
他砍斷了電線 一點光亮也沒有
He cut the wires in the electrical boxes, killed all the lights.
他們就看不到了
So they couldn't see.
他想逼他們迷路 然後在黑暗中狩獵
He wanted to force them off the trail so he could hunt them in the dark.
如果他們看不到 他也看不到啊
If they couldn't see, he couldn't.
他很可能使用某種夜視輔助裝備 像獵人會使用的觀察鏡之類
He probably used some kind of night vision aid, like a scope,something a hunter would use.
她的頸動脈被割斷 眼球也不見了 和其他受害者一樣
Her carotid was severed, and her eyes are missing, just like the others.
他沒有挖男孩的眼睛
He didn't take the boy's eyes.
為什麼不拿? 有什麼特別的嗎?
Well,why not? What's so different?
他左眼有割裂痕跡 而右眼甚至動都沒動
There's a laceration on his left eye, the right eye he didn't even touch.
他手臂上有防禦傷 他很可能試圖反抗 保護女孩
He'sot defenounds on his arms. He probably tried to fight back to protect the girl.
在搏鬥的過程中 不明嫌犯 可能是傷到了他的眼睛
During the fight,the unsub could have cut his eye.
我們覺得他可能是在收集眼睛 要是他需要的是一對呢?
We said he might be collecting them. What if he needs a set?
那樣的損傷 毀了他的藏品
An injury like that ruins the collection.
它們是戰利品 我的天吶 什麼?
They're trophies. Oh,my god. What?
我知道這可能聽起來荒唐 但你聽我說完
I know this sounds crazy, but just hear me out.
動物標本剝制師?
A taxidermist?
Morgan還真可能說到點子了
Morgan might be onto something.
不明嫌犯收集成對的眼睛 而且必須完美無缺
The unsub's collecting sets of eyes that need to be flawless.
他是把他們作為戰利品保存的
Because he's preserving them as a trophy of some kind.
我們說過他是個獵手 獵人收集什麼做戰利品?
We said he was a hunter. What do hunters collect for trophies?
如果他並不是個醫生呢? 這樣就說得通了
What if we're wrong about him being a doctor? It makes sense.
動物標本剝制師擁有保存眼睛 和其他身體部位所需的所有技巧和工具
A taxidermist has all the skills and supplies needed to preserve eyes and other body parts.
他們知道如何像這樣精確摘除眼睛嗎?
Do they know how to surgically remove eyes like this?
是的 他們掌握解剖學知識
Yeah,they have anatomy knowledge.
他們要割下獸皮 就必須 一路切開肌肉 組織 神經
They have to cut through muscle,tissue,and nerves in order to remove hide.
這和摘除眼球是完全一樣的
It's the exact same thing for eyeballs.
Garcia 我開免提了
Garcia,you're on speaker.
同志們 我交叉比對了John O'Heron 和俄城動物標本剝制師名單
Comrades,i crossreferenced this john o'heron with okie city animal stuffers.
六周前 他開過一張250美元支票 作為Lloyd野外狩獵店的保證金
Turns out he wrote a $250 check as some sort of deposit for lloyd's wild game shop 6 weeks ago.
而這個地方離我們第一個受害者被 棄屍的那條田間路不到一英里
Now,this place is scant miles from the farm road where our first victim was dumped.
Lloyd有什麼記錄嗎?
Does lloyd have a record?
Lloyd Bulford有一條 近期官方記錄 而那是...
Lloyd bulford has one recent record from the city,and it is...
一張死亡證明 他四周前死了
A death certificate. He died 4 weeks ago.
死因是? 肺氣腫
Of what? Emphysema.
有曾有犯罪記錄的員工嗎?
Any employees with criminal records?
他根本沒有用人記錄
He's got no employment records at all.
他有一個28歲的兒子叫Earl 與他同住
He has a 28yearold son named earl who lives with him
有一項輕微犯罪記錄 三項虐待動物指控
who has a petty crime record and 3 counts of animal cruelty.
Garcia找出這兒子的所有資料 好滴
Garcia,get everything on the son. Okeydokey.
Morgan我們可能找到疑犯了
Morgan,we may have someone.
俄克拉荷馬城市信託銀行來電
I'm calling from oklahoma city bank and trust.
這是我們第五次試圖 與Earl bulford先生聯繫
This is our fifth attempt to reach mr. Earl bulford.
我們只是想提醒您 您必須 收拾好您的私有物品
We just want to remind you that you need to collect all your belongings
在本週日前搬出該房產
and vacate the premises by sunday.
眼睛不對
The eyes aren't right.
你爸爸呢? 他得弄好這對眼睛
Where's your dad? He's gotta fix those eyes.
眼睛很好 你不會處理眼睛!
The eyes are good. You can't do eyes!
給我! 我拿到別家去
Here! I'm taking it somewhere else.
你不會處理眼睛
You can't do eyes.
有沒有精神疾病的記錄?
Is there any record of mental illness?
沒 但媽媽有眼睛慢性病變史 叫視網膜色素變性
No,but mom had a degenerative eye disease called retinitis pigmentosa,
會最終導致她完全失明 而考慮到他犯下的這些罪行
which would eventually lead her to go blind, and considering his crimes,
那太詭異了 對吧?
that's super weird,right?
還有 她在他8歲那年死於一場車禍
So,anyway,she died in a car accident when he was 8,
其後他被學校開除 原因是和另一個孩子打架
and then he gets expelled from school for getting in a fight with a kid
並試圖把那孩子的眼睛挖出來
and trying to gouge the kid's eyes out.
我沒有找到他回學校上學的記錄 也沒有工作的記錄
I have no record of him returning to school, he has no employment records,
他從來沒有報過稅 名下也沒有信用卡
he's never filed for taxes, he doesn't have a credit card in his name.
除了駕照以外 沒有他任何記錄
Besides his driver's license, there's no record on him at all.
難怪他沒有 出現在我們任何一張清單上
That's probably why he didn't show up on any of our lists.
聽起來他像是完全依靠他爸爸
Sounds like he's totally dependent on his dad,
而爸爸死後 就沒人再關照他了
and when dad dies, there's no one left to check up on him.
爸爸開一輛1990年產 深棕色狩獵牌小貨車
Ok,dad drove a 1990 darkbrown chevy cargo van.
大新聞 債權人這周收房子了 並依法對其經營的事業使置留權
Hot news…creditors took the house this week, and a lien was put on the business.
失去了爸爸 他的房子 現在連家族事業也要丟了
Lost his dad,his house, about to lose the family business.
還用研究應激源嗎?
Care to choose a stressor?
我和Brantley負責後面
I'll take the back with brantley.
這堥S發現貨車 收到
There's no van here. Copy.
什麼也沒發現
I don't see anything.
Hotch我看見血了 我們進去了
Hotch,i see blood. We're going in.
沒有危險
Clear.
那肯定是John O'Heron的血
That's gotta be john o'heron's blood.
他來看他的動物標本 他們起了爭執 然後這一幕就發生了
So he comes here to see his animal, they argue, and then this happens.
沒有危險
Clear.
他睡在這
He's been sleeping here.
如果他現在不在這 那肯定又到外面獵捕去了
Well,if he's not here now, then he's out hunting again.
這個沒有眼睛
這個也沒有
Neither does this one.
這個有
This one does.
那些眼睛 就是派這個用處
This is what's he's doing with the eyes.
看這些
Look at these.
他從小就開始打獵了
He's been hunting since he was a kid.
沒上過學 他很可能 整個童年都待在這
Never went to school. Probably spent his entire childhood in here.
一個人在社交上如此孤立 難怪有精神問題
Somebody this socially isolated no doubt has mental issues.
看起來他只知道兩件事 打獵和剝皮做標本
Looks like he only knew two things… hunting and taxidermy.
只要爸爸還管著他 就沒事
Which was fine as long as daddy was supervising him.
如今把門兒的不在了 就不知何去何從
Now his gatekeeper's gone and he's loose.
請 就放在那邊好了 是 女士
Right over there, please. Yes,ma'am.
這比你們說的可要遲多了
This is much later than you guys said it was gonna be.
讓我看看
Let me see it.
我爸爸一定會非常喜歡的
My daddy's gonna love it.
怎麼了?
What?
我想要你點東西
I need something from you.
我想他全部的客戶資料都在這了
I think this is all of his customer information.
Morgan Prentiss 等等
Morgan,prentiss. Wait.
這個地址  交點路 離那兩名少女被殺地點很近
This address, junction road, it's close to where the teenage girls got killed.
我認為他的襲擊範圍遍佈全鎮 但都在客戶住處附近
I think he's attacking all over town close to where his customers live.
我認識這個客戶 枯河路 就在慢跑者被殺的公園附近
I know the customer on dry creek road, close to where that jogger got killed in the park.
上周那對情侶被殺的地方呢?
And what about where the couple was murdered last night?
臨近這個地址 在這
Close to this address here.
所以說 他是送這些動物標本 去客戶家
Ok,so he's delivering these animals to his clients' homes
然後在社區附近逗留尋找受害人
and then sticking around the neighborhood to find victims.
這媮晹釣潃茼a址
And there are 2 more addresses here.
好吧 我們分頭行動 我馬上派人手去這些地點
All right,we should split up and go. I'll get units to these locations.
好的 非常感謝
All right, thank you so much.
住Bleaker那邊的女士 今天都沒有見過他
The woman at the bleaker address hasn't seen him today.
其他住址 也都沒有反饋
No response at the other residence.
搞什麼鬼?
What the hell?
有什麼事嗎?
May I lp you?
我是FBI的Hotchner探員 這是Brantley隊長
I'm agent hotchner with the fbi. This is lieutenant brantley.
我們能進去嗎? 可以
May we come in? Yeah.
你今天收到這個男人 從動物標本製作鋪送來的貨了嗎?
Did you get a delivery today from a taxidermy shop from this man?
是 我收到了 對我所在區域發全境通告
Yes,i did. I need an apb in my area.
這是多久之前的事? 大概一個小時前
How long ago was this? About an hour ago.
他說他想要我點東西
He said he needed something from me.
我還有餘款未付 我給了錢他就走了
The balance I owed. I paid him and he left.
嚇得我魂飛魄散的 這對是玻璃的
He creeped the hell out of me. These are glass.
是什麼事情?
What is this about?
Hotchner探員 他們找到貨車了 離這很近
Agent hotchner. They found the van. It's close.
失陪
Excuse us.
他一定就在附近 你沿這條街向北
He must be close by. You take the street to the north.
救命!
Help!
Motor路和Descanso路附近 我需要支援
I need backup near motor and descanso.
FBI! Earl! 放開她!
Fbi,earl! Get off of her!
我們抓到他了 抓到他了! 叫救護車!
We got him. We got him! Call an ambulance!
我們需要醫療支援 8800街區 Descanso路南側
We need medical assistance. 8800 block of descanso, south side of the street.
看好他
Secure him.
你能聽見我說話嗎? 醫生馬上就到 別動
Can you hear me? Help is on the way. Hold still.
別動
Hold still.
等我們回去你可以和FBI的人談
You can talk to the fbi when we come back.
這堳蝏穧^事? 他一個人把他制服了
What happened here? Took him down by himself.
Hotch
Hotch.
Brantley說你單槍匹馬制服他的
Brantley says you took him down solo.
他就在我後面不遠
He wasn't far behind me.
你知道應該等支援的
You know you should have waited for backup.
你會嗎?
Would you have?
笑啥? 沒事
What? Nothing.
抓到他了 我們馬上回家
We got him. We're coming home.
大伙太棒了 彼此彼此
You guys rock. Right back at you.
特別任務做得如何了?
So how are you doing on that special ops mission?
完成任務 我一點也不懷疑 再見
Mission accomplished. I had no doubt. Bye.
存咯~
Keep it.
就是他了
There he is.
小組的人回酒店收拾行李了
The team's at the hotel packing.
一小時後回程 覺得可以嗎?
You think we can leave in about an hour?
好 好 我們盡量趕 嘿 那是我的東西
Yeah. Yeah,we can try. Hey,that's my stuff.
那些東西你從哪來的?
Where did you get that stuff?
小聲點
Keep your voice down.
那人很壞的 他死有餘辜
That guy was mean. He deserved it.
你知道 你的眼睛... 實在是相當漂亮
You know,you've got... Real pretty eyes.
把他帶出去 快點
Get him out of here…now.
抱歉
Sorry.
JJ 他們在鋪子媯o現其他人眼了嗎?
Jj,did they find any more human eyes at the shop?
是 有一些 他們還在找
Yeah,a few. They're still looking.
他們希望能找到所有受害者的眼睛
They're hoping to match the eyes to the rest of the victims.
聽著 我可能需要不止一小時
Uh,listen,i may need more than an hour.
Sukarto女士
Ms.Sukarto.
Morgan探員 你們找到了嗎?
Agent morgan. Did you find them?
我們找到了 它們現在還在驗屍官辦公室
We did. They're at the coroner's office right now.
首先得走取證程序
They need to be processed for evidence first,
但明天就可以送到 您選好殯儀館了
but they can be sent to the funeral home of your choice tomorrow.
你不知道這對我們來說意味著什麼
You have no idea what this means to us.
真希望你姐姐能安息了
I really hope your sister can rest in peace now.
晚安
Good night.
"生於靜 生於汝生之本
"dwell in peace in the home of your own being,
則死亡之兆 亦將不得近汝"
and the messenger of death will not be able to touch you."
聖人那納克 (印度錫克教創始人)
guru nanak.
待得這麼晚呀
You are here late.
寫報告嘛
Reports.
現在我才明白為什麼Hotch 一直都比我們所有人要走得晚
Hotch always stayed later than the rest of us, and now I understand why.
他現在不用再寫報告了 為什麼還在這?
He doesn't have to write them anymore. Why is he still here?
我不知道
I don't know.
但 我知道我需要休息
But I do know I need to get some rest.
還有另外一個案子 明天開始
I got another case starting tomorrow.
嗯 我...你走之前 能幫我 從倉庫拿點東西出來嗎?
Um,i…before you go, can you help me get something out of storage?
好的 寶貝姑娘 聽你差遣 謝謝你
Yes,baby girl. Anything for you. Thank you.
嘿 那是什麼? 之前沒見過嘛
Hey,what's that? I haven't seen it before.
Penelope 你沒見過的東西還多著呢
Penelope,there's a lot of my stuff that you haven't seen before.
哇 你就愛調戲人玩
Wow,you are a tease.
瞅瞅
Voila.
我們來Hall的辦公室幹什麼?
What are we doing in hall's office?
呃 這已經不算是Hall的辦公室了 這是你的辦公室
Um,it's kind of not hall's office anymore. It's your office.
什麼? JJ打了幾個電話
What? Jj made some calls.
Hall探員一個月後就退休了 但最後一點工作 可以在家完成
Agent hall's retiring in a month, but he's finishing his caseload at home,
於是 趁你們都不在的時候 老娘捲起袖子挪走了他所有的箱子
so,while you all were away, mama set to work clearing out the rest of his boxes
然後為我們的臨時小組負責人 佈置好一間稱頭的高級辦公室
and setting up an uber office fit for our acting unit chief.
Garcia 這是真的?
Garcia,this is for real?
按我的品味來說 這有點遜了 但我想 得配上你的行政等級
It's kind of blah for my taste, but I figured you needed to keep up with agency standards.
不過還是... 佈置了屬於你的...
I did make you your own...
秘密樂園
Secret fun zone.
女人 你瘋了
Woman, you have lost your mind.
但 你是最棒你
But you are the best.
我完全同意 過來
I completely agree. Come here.
不打擾你了 你就好好標記你的領地吧
I will leave you alone to mark your territory.
真的 謝謝你了
Thank you. Very much.
永遠樂意為你效勞
You are ever so welcome.
是我
It's me.
是 我回來了  聽著 呃...
Yeah,i'm back. Listen,uh...
那喝一杯的邀請還有效嗎?
Does that offer for a drink still stand?
犯罪心理 第五季 第6集 眼殤
== 結束 ==
Criminal Minds Season05 Episode06 The Eyes Have It